While the world was falling apart, they were falling in love.
Ali and Nino is a drama, romance film directed by Asif Kapadia.
Muslim prince Ali and Georgian aristocrat Nino have grown
up in the Russian province of Azerbaijan.
Their tragic love story sees the outbreak of the First World
War and the world’s struggle for Baku’s oil.
Ultimately they must choose to fight for their
country’s independence or for each other.
Ali Khan Shirvanshir, played by Adam Bakri.
Nino Kipiani, played by María Valverde.
Duchess Kipiani, played by Connie Nielsen.
Duke Kipiani, played by Mandy Patinkin.
Seyid Mustafa, played by Numan Acar.
Malik Nakhararyan, played by Riccardo Scamarcio.
Ali and Nino is a 2016 British-Azerbaijani war film, based on
Kurban Said's 1937 novel of the same name.
The film is written by Christopher Hampton and directed by Asif Kapadia.
It stars Maria Valverde and Adam Bakri.
The tone is emotional.